Inventory of the Tibor Flórián papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Tibor Flórián papers
1926-1996
2006C18
Hoover Institution Archives
109 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (56.35 linear feet)
Correspondence, transcripts and sound recordings of radio broadcasts, poems and other writings, memoranda, reports, printed matter, and memorabilia relating to Radio Free Europe broadcasts to Hungary, the Hungarian Revolution of 1956, Hungarian émigré affairs, Hungarian-language publishing in the United States, and international freedom for writers issues.
Flórián, Tibor, 1908-
Access
Boxes 97-109 are closed; remainder of collection is open for research. Collection stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2006.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Eckhardt (Tibor) papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Gábor (Áron) papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Hungarian subject collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Pásztor (László) papers, Hoover Institution Archives
RFE/RL broadcast records, Hoover Institution Archives
RFE/RL corporate records, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1908 April 12 Born, Selmecbánya, Austro-Hungary (present-day Banská Štiavnica, Slovakia)
1927 Graduated, Roman Catholic Lyceum, Cluj (in Hungarian: Kolozsvár), Romania
1934 Graduated, University of Cluj, law degree
1934-1945 Active member of Hungarian literary circles in Cluj; probably resided and worked for most of this time in Gherla (in Hungarian: Szamosújvár), Romania
1935 Author, Felhők fölött, felhők alatt, a book of poetry
1936 Author, Vázlatok, a book of poetry
1945 Immigrated to Germany
1945-1949 Resided in the town of Cham
1945-1954 Married to Áva Felföldy
1945-1949 Literary editor of the émigré weekly Hungaria; at some point an employee of the American Red Cross; a member of émigré organizations and a contributor to émigré periodicals, from this time on and throughout his life
1946 Author, Kőtáblák öszetörtek, a book of poetry
1948 Author, Mélység fölött, a book of poetry
1949 Immigrated to the United States
1949-1986 Resided in New Jersey and Connecticut
1950-1974 Announcer and later Editor, Radio Free Europe, New York City, N.Y.
1954-1974? Board Member of Kossuth Publishing Co. (Kossuth Kiadó), New York City and Cleveland, Ohio
1955 Married Sophie Weress
1955-1986? Board Member, mostly Treasurer, of American Branch of International P.E.N.: Writers in Exile, New York City
1960?-1986 Member and Board Member of Arpad Academy (Árpád Akadémia), Cleveland
1966?-1986? Member and Board Member of American Transylvanian Federation (Amerikai Erdélyi Szövetség), New York City
1975 Author, Keserű gyökéren, a book of poetry
1986 March 2 Died, Punta Gorda, Florida
Scope and Content of Collection
The Tibor Flórián papers document Hungarian-American cultural and political activities, including responses to the 1956 Hungarian Revolution and activities on behalf of the Hungarian community in Transylvania, as well as Hungarian-language publishing in the United States, and international freedom for writers issues. Materials include correspondence with Hungarian émigrés, especially writers and journalists, mostly in the United States, South America, Germany and Australia; transcripts, sound recordings, and other materials of the Radio Free Europe Hungarian service; and Flórián's poetry, essays, and other writings.
Radio Free Europe.; Radio broadcasting--Hungary.; Hungary--History--Revolution, 1956.; Hungarians--United States.; Hungarian literature.; Kossuth Publishing Company.; PEN (Organization); Civil rights.; Audiotapes.
- Alphabetical file, circa 1942-1990 (Boxes 1-12)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains mostly correspondence with other writers and with editors of Hungarian periodicals, writings and related materials. Arranged alphabetically and then chronologically.
  - Ágoston, Ede, correspondence, writings and related materials, 1973-1976 (Box 1)
  - Almási, Gyula, correspondence, artwork, Flórián's writings, 1971-1973, undated (Box 1)
  - Amerikai Magyar Kiadó and Ferenc Mérő, correspondence and clippings, 1964-1970, undated (Box 1)
  - Balogh, Dezső de A., autobiographical sketch, undated (Box 1)
  - Balogh, Lajos and others, 1948-1954, undated (Box 1)
    Contains correspondence, poems, financial documents, a photograph signed "Jóska"; most materials are related to József Nyírő.
  - Bán, Oszkár, correspondence and writings, 1967-1977, undated (Box 1)
  - Béky, Zoltán, Bishop, correspondence and clippings, 1973-1976, undated (Box 1)
  - Bereczky, Emma, correspondence, 1954-1963, undated (Box 1)
  - Berzy, József, Magyar Ház, Toronto, Canada, correspondence, 1977-1983, undated (Box 2)
  - Borbándi, Gyula, correspondence, 1966-1976, undated (Box 2)
  - Bretan, Nicolae, 1971-1983 (Box 2)
    Contains correspondence with Judit Bretan Le Bovit, Radio Free Europe scripts and similar materials.
  - "Budapesti piarista évfordulója (400.) a kolozsvári Alma Maternak,", 1979 (Box 2)
    Contains correspondence and Flórián's writings.
  - Carter, Hodding, III, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    Contains Flórián's letter to President Jimmy Carter protesting the return of St. Stephen's crown to Hungary and Hodding Carter's response to the letter.
  - Chomos, Sándor, The Eighth Tribe - A Nyolcadik Törzs, correspondence and Flórián's writings, 1979-1981, undated (Box 2)
  - Csegezi, József, correspondence and writings, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Csóka, Jenő, correspondence, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Danó, Sándor, correspondence, 1964-1965, undated (Box 2)
  - Dékány, László, New Yorki Napló, correspondence, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Detroiti Ujság and Antal Koósa, correspondence and related materials, 1968-1985 (Box 2)
  - Dobolyi, Árpád, correspondence and Flórián's writings, 1981-1982, undated (Box 2)
  - Enczi, Endre, Irodalmi Ujság, correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 2)
  - Fáy, István, correspondence and articles, 1980-1985, undated (Box 2)
  - Fényes, Mária de Csokaly, Californiai Magyarság, correspondence and Flórián's writings, 1971-1986 (Box 2)
  - Gábor, Áron, corrrespondence, clippings and related materials, 1968-1969, undated (Box 2)
  - Gombos, Zoltán, Liberty Publishing Co., correspondence and Flórián's writings, 1966-1975, undated (Box 3)
  - Grósz, József, correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Gyallay, Domokos, correspondence, Radio Free Europe scripts and related materials, 1963-1970, undated (Box 3)
  - Gyimesi, Gyula, correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 3)
  - Haraszti, Endre, correspondence, 1979-1984 (Box 3)
  - Harsona Lap- és Könyvkiadó Vállalat, Croydon, England, correspondence and Flórián's writings, 1965-1983, undated (Box 3)
  - Határ, Győző, correspondence, promotional materials, and Flórián's speech, 1970-1978 (Box 3)
  - Heckenast, Noémi, correspondence and writings, 1976-1979 (Box 3)
  - Horváth, Sándor, writings, 1961, undated (Box 3)
  - Hungarian Society of Boston, 1977, undated (Box 3)
    Contains correspondence, Flórián's speech, biographical notes, and related materials.
  - Igady-Kiss, Alexander T., correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Ilia, Mihály, correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Illyés, Elemér, correspondence, clippings and related materials, 1975-1978, undated (Box 3)
  - International Broadcasters Association, correspondence and newsletters, 1977-1990 (Box 3)
  - Itt-Ott, correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 3)
  - Izráeli Kurír, György Rezes and Margalit Gondos, correspondence, articles and related documents, 1976-1978, undated (Box 3)
  - József Attila Irodalmi Kör, correspondence and related materials, 1985, undated (Box 3)
  - Kanadai Magyar Ujság, correspondence, 1958-1976 (Box 3)
  - Kanadai Magyarság, correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 4)
  - Karola, Béla, correspondence and an interview, undated (Box 4)
  - Kemenes Géfin, László correspondence, 1978-1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Képes Magyar Világhíradó, correspondence, 1963-1977, undated (Box 4)
  - Kerecsendi Kiss, László, correspondence, 1960-1964 (Box 4)
  - Kisjókai, Erzsébet, correspondence, writings and related materials, 1958-1981, undated (Box 4)
  - Kiss, Margit, correspondence and writings, 1971-1972, undated (Box 4)
  - Klamár, Gyula, Bécsi Magyar Híradó, correspondence, clippings and Flórián's writings, 1968-1978, undated (Box 4)
  - Kocsis, Gábor, correspondence and presentation materials, 1973, undated (Box 4)
  - Kostya, Sándor, Magyar Ház, Toronto, Canada, correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 4)
  - Kótay, Zoltán, Kárpát Publishing Co., correspondence, 1963-1976 (Box 4)
  - Kovács, Imre, correspondence, also with PEN, and writings, 1977, undated (Box 4)
  - Kriterion, Bucharest, Romania, correspondence, promotional materials and financial documents, 1972-1975, undated (Box 4)
  - Kutasi Kovács, Lajos, correspondence, writings and related materials, 1953-1964, undated (Box 5)
  - Lévay de Tar, Pálma, correspondence and writings, 1983-1986, undated (Box 5)
  - Lux, András, correspondence and writings, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Magyar Élet, correspondence and related materials, 1967-1984, undated (Box 5)
  - Magyar Kulturális Szövetség and Nyugati Magyar Írók, 1949 (Box 5)
    Contains announcements, mostly on behalf of Cardinal József Mindszenty, and related materials.
  - Magyar Nők, Munich, Germany, correspondence, 1955-1964, undated (Box 5)
  - Márai, Sándor, correspondence, broadcast scripts, articles, 1953-1986, undated (Box 5)
  - Mécs, László, print proofs of a book in Hungarian and English, undated (Box 5)
  - Méder, Zoltán, typescript entitled "Elveszett évek,", undated (Box 6)
  - Megyery, Ella de, correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 6)
  - Méray, Tibor, Irodalmi Ujság, correspondence, 1972-1985 (Box 6)
  - Miklóssi, István, Corvin Publishing Co., correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
  - Mindszenty, József, Cardinal, émigré campaigns against his arrest, writings about him in typescript and published, related materials, circa 1949-1975 (Box 6)
  - Molnár, Ferenc, play in manuscript, undated (Box 6)
  - Mózsi, Ferenc, correspondence and writings, 1975-1984, undated (Box 7)
  - Murányi, Zsóka, correspondence and writings, 1964, undated (Box 7)
  - Nemes Nagy, Ágnes, correspondence and poetry, circa 1968 (Box 7)
  - Nyírő, József, correspondence and related documents: also Lajos Balogh, Ilona Nyírő, and others, 1942-1953, 1964-1980, undated (Box 7)
  - Ohlbaum, Sándor, correspondence, 1964-1975 (Box 7)
  - Orbán, Árpád, correspondence, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Orbán, Blanka and Ference, Új Világ, 1975-1985 (Box 8)
  - Ősze, András, correspondence, articles and related materials, 1969-1986 (Box 8)
  - Padányi-Gulyás, Jenő, correspondence and writings, 1958, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Pálinkás, László, correspondence, 1960 (Box 8)
  - Perthi Magyar Hírek, correspondence and Flórián's writings, 1978-1984 (Box 8)
  - Publishing of Flórián's poetry books, circa 1972-1977 (Box 8)
    Contains book orders, correspondence, and related materials.
  - Rákóczi Foundation, correspondence and promotional materials, 1984-1985 (Box 9)
  - Reményi, József, correspondence, 1947-1954 (Box 9)
  - Reményik, Sándor, circa 1952-1968 (Box 9)
    Contains writings about him and related materials.
  - Rozanich, István and Júlia, correspondence, 1960-1985 (Box 9)
  - Rudnay, Endre, correspondence, 1955-1962 (Box 10)
  - San Franciscói Magyar Híradó, correspondence and Flórián's writings, 1978, undated (Box 10)
  - Solymosi, Zoltán, Kanadai Magyar Írók Szövetsége, correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 10)
  - Solymossy, Olivér, novel in manuscript, entitled "Miért,", undated (Box 10)
  - Somogyi Ferenc, correspondence, 1976-1985 (Box 10)
  - St.-Ivanyi, Alexander (Sándor), correspondence, 1962-1973 (Box 10)
  - Stankovich, Viktor, correspondence and related materials, 1969 (Box 10)
  - Stirling, György, correspondence with Flórián and others, and related materials, 1976-1985, undated (Box 10)
  - Szabó, László, correspondence and Flórián's writings, 1981-1984, undated (Box 11)
  - Szász, Béla, correspondence and related materials, 1951-1964, undated (Box 11)
  - Szász, Lóránt, correspondence, 1974-1977, undated (Box 11)
  - Szathmáry, Lajos, presentation materials, 1970, undated (Box 11)
  - Szebedinszky, Jenő, Magyarság, correspondence, 1953-1979 (Box 11)
  - Szilárd, Marcell, correspondence, 1952 (Box 11)
  - Sztojka, László, typescripts, 1973, undated (Box 11)
  - Tábory, Maxim, correspondence and writings, 1978-1985, undated (Box 11)
  - Thiery, Ákos and Ilona, correspondence and writings, 1974-1985, undated (Box 11)
  - Torjai-Szabó, István, correspondence and writings, 1952-1969, undated (Box 11)
  - Tóth, Imre, correspondence and materials on Hungarian cultural activities in Turkey, 1969-1982, undated (Box 11)
  - Tũz, Tamás, correspondence and Flórián's writings, 1969-1982, undated (Box 12)
  - Új Európa, correspondence and Flórián's writings, 1969-1981, undated (Box 12)
  - Várhely, Emery, correspondence, also with András Zsigmond, and writings, 1982-1984 (Box 12)
  - Varró, Dezső, correspondence and writings, 1973, undated (Box 12)
  - Varsányi, Gyula, correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
  - Vass, Ferenc, correspondence, 1975-1978, undated (Box 12)
  - Vígh, Ildikó, correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 12)
  - Voice of America, broadcast typescripts, 1951, undated (Box 12)
  - Washingtoni krónika, correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
  - Wass, Albert, 1949, undated (Box 12)
    Contains print proofs of a book and an attached letter signed "Gábor."
  - Zilahy, Lajos articles, correspondence and related materials, 1962-1963 (Box 12)
- Chronological correspondence file, circa 1938-1996 (Boxes 12-40)
  May contain correspondence from persons or organizations represented in the alphabetical file and additional materials attached to the letters.
  - Other correspondents in this file
    - Aldobolyi Nagy Miklós
    - Almássy-Balogh, Dezső
    - Alt, Áva
    - Bagossy, László
    - Balogh, Ferenc
    - Bányász, Ferenc
    - Baráth, Anna
    - Betegh, Ernő
    - Betegh, Péter
    - Biró, Béla L.
    - Bodás, János Pál
    - Borshy Kerekes, György
    - Botond, István
    - Buza, John Geo
    - Csíky, Ágnes Mária
    - Czövek, István
    - Dombrády, Dóra
    - Domokos, Pál Péter
    - Domokos Sándor
    - Duska, László
    - Endes, László
    - Erdős, Lajos
    - Erdélyi, József
    - Erős, András
    - Ferdinandy, Mihály
    - Faludy, György
    - Farkas, Ervin
    - Fáy, Ferenc
    - Feketéné Korény, Livia
    - Gácsér, Imre
    - Gereben, István B.
    - Gondos, Margalit
    - Gyimesi, Károly
    - Györgyey, Klára
    - Hegyi, Zoltán
    - Héjjás, Tibor
    - Hellebrandt, Elena Maria de
    - Hoffer, Leopold
    - Holusa, Bert A.
    - Horváth, Elek
    - Juhász, Joseph J.
    - Kabdebó, Tamás
    - Kádás, Imre
    - Kállay, Miklós
    - Kardos, Béla
    - Kedves, András
    - Kiss, Márton Kerecsendi
    - Könnyũ, László
    - Koncz, Anton
    - Korponay, Miklós
    - Kossányi, József
    - Láczay, Ervin
    - Lantos, Ferenc
    - Lehoczky, Gergely
    - Litvay, Julia de
    - Makk, Imre
    - Makkai, ádám
    - Máté, Imre
    - Medveczky, Margit
    - Mikes, Imre
    - Molnár, Gyula
    - Molnár, Imre Székely
    - Nádas, Gyula
    - Nádas, János
    - Nagy, Csaba
    - Nagy, László
    - Negyesy, Irén
    - Nehéz, Ferenc
    - Palotay, István
    - Papp, Gábor
    - Papp, Remig A.
    - Perjesi, Peter
    - Petry, Béla A.
    - Pogány, András H.
    - Romhányi, Árpád
    - Saáry, Áva
    - Sátory, Richárd
    - Simon, Zoltán
    - Sisa, István
    - Somody, István
    - Somody, Pál
    - Szász, József
    - Szeleczky, Zita
    - Szent Miklosy, Balint
    - Szentendrey, Gyula
    - Szeplaki, Joseph
    - Szerdahelyi, László
    - Szilágyi, Oliver
    - Szurcsik, Joseph
    - Teleki, Béla
    - Tomek, Vince
    - Udvari, Mária
    - Vajay, Szabolcs de
    - Varga, László
    - Varró, József
    - Vatai, László
    - Veréb, László
    - Viharos, Viktor
    - Vladár, Pál
    - Zolcsák, István
    - Zsuffka, Viktor
  - 1938-1946 and probably 1940s (Box 12)
  - 1947-1948 (Box 13)
  - 1949 (Boxes 13-14)
  - Probably 1950s (Box 14)
  - 1950 (Boxes 14-15)
  - 1951 (Boxes 15-16)
  - 1952 (Box 16)
  - 1953 (Boxes 16-17)
  - 1954-1957 (Box 17)
  - 1958-1962 and probably 1960s (Box 18)
  - 1963-1967 (Box 19)
  - 1968-1972 and probably 1970s (Box 20)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - 1975 (Box 22)
  - 1976 (Boxes 23-24)
  - 1977 (Boxes 24-25)
  - 1978 (Boxes 25-26)
  - 1979 (Boxes 26-27)
  - Probably 1980s (Box 27)
  - 1980 (Boxes 28-29)
  - 1981 (Boxes 29-30)
  - 1982 (Boxes 30-32)
  - 1983 (Boxes 32-34)
  - 1984 (Boxes 34-36)
  - 1985 (Boxes 36-38)
  - 1986 (Box 38)
  - Condolence letters and related materials, 1986 (Boxes 38-39)
  - Correspondence addressed to Sophie Flórián, 1990-1996 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence fragments and undated (Box 40)
- Hungarian cultural and political activities file, circa 1948-1986 (Boxes 40-48)
  Covers mainly activities of those organizations which Flórián belonged to or had contacts with, mainly in the United States: the American Transylvanian Federation (Amerikai Erdélyi Szövetség), Arpad Academy (Árpád Akadémia), Magyar Piarista Diákszövetség (Hungarian Piarist Alumni Association), Magyar Szabadságharcos Szövetség (Hungarian Freedom Fighters Federation) and others, and contains correspondence, promotional materials and related matter, arranged generally in original order.
- Kossuth Kiadó (Kossuth Publishing Co.) documents, circa 1951-1974 (Boxes 49-51)
  Correspondence, internal documents, and other materials related to the publishing of Hungarian-language publications, arranged generally in original order.
- Radio Free Europe materials, circa 1951-1973 (Boxes 51-56)
  Correspondence, transcripts of programs, promotional materials and related matter, arranged generally in original order.
- International PEN, Writers in Exile, American Branch records, circa 1958-1986 (Boxes 56-63)
  Correspondence, internal documents, and promotional materials, arranged generally in original order.
- Personal file, circa 1927-1986 (Boxes 63-66)
  Correspondence, photographs, resumes, legal, financial, and related documents, arranged generally in original order.
- Family file, circa 1945-1986 (Boxes 66-69)
  Correspondence, writings, photographs, legal, financial, and related materials, arranged generally in original order.
  - Photographs (Box 66)
  - Correspondence and poems of Flórián's mother, Aranka / Zlatica Szénássy and other materials about her (Boxes 66-68)
  - Correspondence, legal, financial and similar materials refering to Flórián's relatives and his property holdings in Czechoslovakia (Box 68)
  - Correspondence with Flórián's children and similar related materials (Box 69)
- Writings by and about Flórián, circa 1927-1986 (Boxes 70-92)
  Poetry, prose writings, presentation and lecture materials, essays, published articles, translations of Flórián's poetry and of miscellaneous other writings, musical scores, and notes, as well as related correspondence and other materials, arranged generally in original order.
  - Presentations, essays, poetry, prose writings, published articles, handwritten notes, translations, musical scores, related correspondence and other related materials (Box 70)
  - An article entitled "Reményik Sándor üzen," essays, published articles, Christmas-related essays, correspondence with Dezső Abraham and related Flórián's writings, "Mattyaszovsky Zsolnay Miklós ügy" folder with articles and related materials, literary criticism writings, handwritten notes, poetry, presentations and related materials, translations (Box 71)
  - Essays, published articles, presentations, prose, and other writings (Box 72)
  - Poetry (Box 73)
  - Poetry, prose, essays, published articles, and other writings (Box 74)
  - Essays, other writings, newspaper clippings (Box 75)
  - Translations, poetry, attached correspondence, handwritten notes (Box 76)
  - Translations, Radio Free Europe scripts, other writings, attached correspondence, published writings and other printed matter (Box 77)
  - Poetry, prose writings, by or about Flórián, newspaper clippings (Box 78)
  - Newspaper clippings, other published matter, including obituaries (Box 79)
  - Poetry, essays and prose, mostly in manuscript (Box 80)
  - A manuscript of an interview with Flórián, newspaper clippings (Box 81)
  - Typescripts of his books of poetry, Kőtáblák öszetörtek and Keserũ gyökéren; other poetry, presentations literary criticism on Flórián's works, prose, translations, articles published and in manuscript and related correspondence (Box 82)
  - Translations, literary criticism on Flórián's works; presentations - on József Mindszenty and other; miscellaneous other writings, newspaper clippings, leaflets (Box 83)
  - Prose writings, translations, resumes, and related materials (Box 84)
  - Prose writings and related materials, leaflets (Box 85)
  - Prose and other writings by or about Flórián; Keserũ gyökéren, a book of poetry in typescript and related published materials (Box 86)
  - Miscellaneous writings, leaflets of cultural meetings (Box 87)
  - Presentations, translations; poetry, also by Aranka Szénássy, related writings; typescript of poetry collections Keserũ gyökéren and Keletről jöttem, prose, miscellaneous other writings, related correspondence (Box 88)
  - Print proofs of Keserũ gyökéren, a poetry book; short prose and poetry, including Aranka Szénássy's writings; miscellaneous other writings (Box 89)
  - Published writings by or about Flórián, leaflets, and related correspondence (Box 90)
  - Poems dedicated to Flórián; presentations in connection to Szabad Magyar Ujságírók Szövetsége, related correspondence and other materials; writings by and about Flórián (Box 91)
  - Writings by Flórián, mostly published (Box 92)
- Miscellany (Boxes 92-96)
  - Unidentified photographs, writings or fragments by different authors, ephemera, handwritten notes; promotional materials and similar printed matter (Boxes 92-93)
  - Newspaper clippings, mostly from Hungarian-American periodicals (Boxes 94-96)
- Sound recordings (Boxes 97-109)
  Access
  CLOSED
  Labels, when present, indicate materials for Radio Free Europe programs (especially the Musical Messages) and folk music recordings. Includes 188 sound reels, arranged generally in original order.
  - A song and speech, undated (Box 98)
    Use copy reference number: 2006c18_a_0003368
    The first recording on the tape is a woman singing with piano accompaniment. The second and third recordings are a man speaking dramatically.
  - Fairy tales performed as folk songs, undated (Box 98)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Use copy reference number: 2006c18_a_0003369
    A folk singer narrates and sings renditions of Rumpelstiltskin, the Three Bears, and Cinderella. In English.
  - The rest of the sound recordings are not yet described (Boxes 97-109)
- Oversize materials, circa 1926-1978 (Box 110)
  - Honorary diplomas and plaques